Victor Wright Full Stack Developer



- ◆ Single-Page Apps
- ◆ Multi-Page Apps/server-side rendering
- ◆ Relational Databases
- **♦ RESTful API's**

An extensive expertise over 20years in IT and Management background, encompassing Systems Analysis and Design, software and website development, setup and administration of networks, installation and troubleshooting hardware and software etc. Because of my long management experience, I possess strong corporate and customer-service skills.

TECH STACK

Front-End

- HTML5 / CSS3
- JavaScript ES6 (REACT)
- TypeScript
- Node.JS (Express)
- RESTful API's
- PHP
- Apache Server
 Databases
- MySQL / PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

Otner

- Git (GitHub)
- Vercel / Heroku
- Jason Web Token
- Headless CMS
- WordPress



- +49 176 4677 4278
- http://vrw-gh.github.io/vrw-GH
- in www.linkedin.com/in/victor-r-wright
- victor.wright@outlook.de
- Semmelbergstr 14, Bad Wiessee 83707, Germany.

Freelancer (Online)

09.2020 - present , Germany

EMPLOYMENT

Consultant / Developer / IT Services

Websites • Apps • Graphic Design/Artwork • Web Hosting/Support Services • Hardware-Installation/Setup • LAN/WiFi Networking • Excel (Advanced) • English writing/proofing

Migrated to Germany 08.2020

Permanent move (due to marriage), so I decided to make a career change, to follow my life-long passion of being a Coder / Nerd / IT Expert.

Jude Fernandopulle Associates Pvt. Ltd.

07.2001 - 08.2020. Sri Lanka

The company is a Renewable Energy Provider, engaged in developing, manufacturing, sales and installation of Solar Hotwater and PV Electricity Systems.

During my 20 years here, the company developed from a small, back-yard project with a monthly turnover of <0,3mio in 2001, to grossing over 30,0mio (as at 2020).

http://www.sunbird.lk/

General Manager - Solar Technology Div.

- Full responsibility to develop and maintain the entire IT network: PC's and softwares, document formats, worksheets, physical LAN, switches / routers, NAS, etc.
- Completely overhauled the company website(s) based on WordPress.
- Directly involved in developing the current website(s) in collaboration with developers, plus two web-apps for inquiry management (SBIOS) and sales-turnover (SNOW).
- Developed and still maintaining a datadriven, multi-user, Showroom Inquiry and Proforma Invoice Generation system using Excel365 online.
- Provider of Hosting and Email services.
- Worked with and managed 50+ personnel.
- Gave invaluable ideas and inputs in conceptualizing and expanding our main facility, with modern factory, stores, testing area and office complex.
- Directly involved in setting up 11 regional sales & distribution centres island-wide.
- Spear-headed the new imp/exp department and international outreach programs.

Previous Work History

United Tobacco Processing Pvt. Ltd. 1998-1999, Sri Lanka

Personnel Officer

■ Managing recruitment, staffing, welfare and security.

Holiday Inn Hotel 1998, Sri Lanka

Duty Manager

Front-office, Guest relations and security.

Airwing Tours Pvt. Ltd. 1997-1998, Sri Lanka

Senior Executive - IT & Operations

■ Computerisation of Tour Package & quotes.

Padua Marine Exports

1995-1997, Sri Lanka

Manager-IT / Operations Assistant

■ PC based management of all operations.

GAMA Services Ltd.

1992-1994, Saudi Arabia

Executive Secretary

■ Corporate Catering and Engineering CEO's.

Commercial Leasing Co.

1990-1992, Sri Lanka

Software Developer/Operations Asst.

■ Developed Clipper-based app for operations.

OTHER SKILLS

Computer / IT

- MS Windows
- MS Excel
- MS Word
- CorelDraw
- Adobe Photoshop
- FoxPro & DB tables
- Figma
- UI / UX basics
- Jira / Trello
- Scrum

Networking / Internet

- Web Hosting / Email
- LAN / WAN / Wi-Fi
- Hardware / Network

SOTT SKIIIS

- Communication
- Collaboration & Teamwork
- Comprehension
- Independent work
- Creativity
- Flexibility
- Attention to detail
- Problem-solving
- Service-oriented

LANGUAGES

- (EN) English Native
- (DE) German A2
- (SI) Sinhala Fluent

INTERESTS

- Coding for the Future
- Ideas for Metaverse & Virtual Realities
- Robotics and Automation Systems

Previous Work History - continued

Eskimo Fashion Knitwear (Lanka) Ltd.

1987-1989, Sri Lanka

Management Trainee

■ Product Design, Production, Quality Control, Workforce, Maintenance of knitting machines.

QUALIFICATIONS

WBS Coding School

09.2021 - 01.2022 - Germany

A project based, practice oriented, collaborative coding training as a full-time remote bootcamp (600hrs).

Full-Stack Web & App Development

Final Project: "Share My Food"
Developed using the P.E.R.N. stack:http://vrw-gh.github.io/final-project-wd020

EDP Services (Pvt) Ltd.

05.1990 -05.1991 - Sri Lanka.

A comprehensive, full-time course (12 months) covering Systems Analysis and Designwith over 180hrs practical work on PCs and Mainframes.

Diploma in Information Technology

Final Project: "Design of IT System for Leasing Operations" at :-

Commercial Leasing Company - Sri Lanka

SCHOOLING

Maris Stella College

01.1975 - 08.1987 - Sri Lanka

General Certificate of Education

Year 13: Physics(+), Maths(-), Chem(-)

REFERENCES

WBS Coding School (Lead Instructor)

Team Lead - Web Dev.

Mr. Jorge Paul

Tel: 0152 0720 4102

jorge.paul@wbscodingschool.com

Ribida

22. Jun. 2022

Bad Wiessee.